good morning everyone my name is khati
from pgdm IB international business
today I'll be discussing some of the
most frequently asked questions by the
students while applying for pgdm course
and here's a bucket of questions that I
have in front of me and I will be
answering three questions today let's
pick up the first
[Music]
question first introduce yourself it may
sound like a very easy question but
trust me uh with my experience first 1
minute of introduction is enough for an
interviewer to decide whether or not he
wants to hire that candidate so make
that one minute count and a word of
advice never repeat your name while
introducing yourself as the interviewer
is already aware of that the second
important question would be to have some
basic knowledge about the knowhow of the
world uh what is happening around it so
I will suggest three National and three
international news is a must another
question question would be instead of
asking about your weaknesses and uh
strengths directly a interviewer can ask
about what are your strengths that
resonate with being a manager so you
should be able to correlate the two of
them and the tip would be uh to share as
much as authentic genuine personal life
experience as possible as it will
validate your statements okay so now
it's time for the second question let's
answer
[Music]
that no if a student doesn't get an
internship the final placement will not
get affected but that is not possible
with our College because Summer
internship is mandatory and it holds six
credits as well uh I think of internship
is uh important as well as you get to
know the Kno how of the corporate flare
and get an exposure as well you are able
to apply your theoretical knowledge in a
practical form and a option that the
college gives is that you can either
choose a placement from the placement
cell of the college or from the outside
that is your choice I think uh from my
experience in international business
pgdm the internships that are offered
are in the areas of supply chain
Logistics shipping import procedures
documentations Etc okay so it's now time
for the final question of the day let's
pick it
[Music]
up yes I think gims provide an excellent
exposure which aligns with the syllabus
as well as with the real life problem
that are happening around the world so
it is very helpful for the students we
just recently had our IB international
business conclave in which top level
industry experts were invited to discuss
on the topics that are most relevant in
that field that is supply chain its
disruptions and Way Forward we have
alumini meets we have guest lectures
like we recently had on Ms word office
for beginners for design thinking we
have industrial visits like we just had
our industrial visit for Mother Dairy
plant while we were studying about plant
location and plant layout and it's
important so in all to sum it up I think
it's a great experience because it is
not just about Theory you get to
visualize the things that you will be
doing 2 years after doing the pgdm so if
you guys have any more doubts do comment
it down and I'll be answering it in the
next
[Music]
video